Finding Aid for the J. Warren Perry Interview Tapes, 1995-2002
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
J. Warren Perry Interview Tapes, 1995-2002
Mus. Arc. 3.6
Perry, J. Warren
1 box (6 audio cassettes, 2 video cassettes)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains 6 cassette recordings of interviews conducted with collector J. Warren Perry and 2 VHS tapes of events in which he was featured.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Cassettes created by Music Library staff and students.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Two copies of each cassette have been retained until it can be determined which copy is the original and preferred for digitizing.
Biographical Note
Dr. J. Warren Perry was born in Richmond, Indiana in 1921. He earned his B.A. at DePauw University in 1944, his Master's at Northwestern University in 1952, and his Ph.D. at Northwestern in 1955. Dr. Perry has been on the faculties at the University of Illinois at Chicago, Northwestern Medical School, and the University of Chicago. He was also employed as deputy assistant commissioner for research and training in the Vocational Rehabilitation Administration at the Department of Health, Education and Welfare in Washington, D.C. Dr. Perry is the founder of the School of Health Related Professions (now the School of Public Health and Health Professions) at the University at Buffalo, The State University of New York. He served as dean of the school from its founding in 1967 until 1977.
Dr. Perry devoted much of his life to supporting the arts. Before moving to Buffalo he was one of the founders of the Lyric Opera Company in Chicago. Since arriving in Buffalo Dr. Perry has served as chairman or board member for several local organizations, including the Buffalo Philharmonic, Community Music School, Theodore Roosevelt Inaugural National Historic Site, Artpark, and Friends of the Center for the Arts. The numerous awards granted to honor Dr. Perry's contributions to the community include the Buffalo Arts Councils' Supporter of the Arts award, the Buffalo Distinguished Citizen Award, and national Outstanding Philanthropist Award. Dr. Perry died August 5, 2010 in Buffalo.
J. Warren Perry was an avid collector of photographs and other artifacts related to music, especially opera and ballet. He worked for the Lyric Opera in Chicago as Director of the Committee on Education. He was interviewed in 1995 by Music Library students, Leah Maragliano and Kathy Blough.
Scope and Content Note
Contains 6 cassette recordings of interviews conducted with collector J. Warren Perry and 2 VHS tapes of events in which he was featured.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
I. Cassette tapes
II. VHS tapes
Container List
- Cassette tapes, 1995, I.; Cassette 1-6
  Chronologically arranged.
  - Interview with J. Warren Perry tape 1, 10 May 1995, 1 cassette (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Interview with J. Warren Perry tape 2, 17 May 1995, 1 cassette (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Interview with J. Warren Perry tape 3, 17 May 1995, 1 cassette (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Interview with J. Warren Perry tape 4, 24 May 1995, 1 cassette (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Interview with J. Warren Perry tape 5, 24 May 1995, 31 May 1995, 1 cassette (Box 1, Item 5)
  - Interview with J. Warren Perry tape 6, 31 May 1995, 1 cassette (Box 1, Item 6)
- VHS tapes, 2000-2002, II.; Item 7-8
  - Arts Council Awards, 2000, 1 VHS cassette; From WKBW-TV. (Box 1, Item 7)
  - J. Warren Perry interview, 16 August 2002, 1 VHS cassette (Box 1, Item 8)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Blough, Kathryn M., 1960-; Maragliano, Leah; State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Subjects
Perry, J. Warren; Opera--20th century
Genres
interviews; audiocassettes
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
J. Warren Perry Collection of Photographs, ca. 1910-1971
Mus. Arc. 3.1
A collection of 2110 photographs, chiefly of opera singers and productions, with additional photographs of conductors, performers, ensembles, and concert halls.